ALYSSA NYCUM

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Your not-so-average zoo keeper turned software developer.

For the last 10 years, I've had the incredible opportunity to work up close and personal with a wide variety of animals. But as priorities in life change, so do careers. As a natural problem-solver with a keen eye for details making the jump to software development wasn't as different from zoo keeping as you might think. Every day brings on new challenges and the idea of a lifetime of learning brings out an excitement in me that I look forward to continue exploring.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, 2020

Intensive, 6-month full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full-stack development fundamentals and problem solving through building individual and group projects utilizing HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, and Python/Django

TOWSON UNIVERSITY, 2012

Bachelor of Science in Animal Behavior Bachelor of Science in Psychology

CONTACT INFORMATION

443-985-6423

alyssa.nycum@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/alyssanycum/ github.com/alyssanycum alyssanycum.github.io/

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School (Jan 2020 - Present)

- Utilizing Git and GitHub for version control
- Creating websites and one-page applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Understanding the importance of using Semantic HTML
- Learning JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular & readable code and reusable components
- Ability to query data using 3rd party APIs and JSON-server, gathering user input through event listeners, and utilizing CRUD functionality

PROJECTS

BetaData

https://github.com/alyssanycum/betadata

- When it comes to climbing in an indoor rock climbing gym, climbs are constantly changing new climbs being put up and old climbs being taken down. It can be difficult to keep track of which climbs you've already climbed. BetaData allows users to record the climbs that they've done as well as any climbing goals that they have. Users have full CRUD functionality on the climbs that they record. They can also add multiple attempts to a climb, add a helpful note about the climb, give each climb an enjoyment rating, filter & sort their climbs in multiple ways, and view charts that display how many climbs of each level they have done.
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, React.js, ReactStrap, Moment.js, Chart.js

Handy Andy

https://github.com/alyssanycum/handyandy

- A social-media dashboard for people to use to organize their daily tasks, events, news articles, friends, and chat messages.
- Group project in which I was responsible for the news, settings, and logout functionality
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, React Semantic UI

Nutshell

https://github.com/alyssanycum/nutshell

- The same project as Handy Andy but built using vanilla JavaScript
- Group project in which I was responsible for the events functionality
- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Hoofstock Keeper

Nashville Zoo (Jun 2018 - December 2019)

- Responsible for all aspects of daily care including feeding, cleaning and maintaining barns and exhibits, assisting with veterinary care, behavioral observation, accurate and detailed record keeping, and daily animal training and enrichment
- Utilized problem-solving skills and attention to detail to make animal management decisions
- · Worked with various teams to ensure the highest standard of animal care
- Revamped training and enrichment programs for primary animals
- Trained and supervised interns
- Educated the public about animal care and conservation through keeper talks, behind the scenes tours, and training demos

OTHER EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Driver Growth Operations Associate

Lyft (Jan 2017 - Jun 2018

- Worked on consistent tasks necessary to daily operations
- Utilized internal tools to take prospective drivers from application to their first passenger
- Identified and solved problems working with various stakeholders
- Conducted quality assurance and provided coaching to local teams and partner sites
- Provided support to applicants through SMS and email
- Built out training decks for Tier 1 Support to take over customer service tasks from the Driver Growth team so time could be used more for operational tasks
- Created project proposals for areas of Lyft's processes that need improvement
- Learned basic SQL to query data used to implement and make improvements to the driver application process
- Conducted A/B tests to collect and analyze data to determine the success of proposed ideas of improvement

Front Desk Manager

Climb Nashville (Feb 2016 - Dec 2016)

- Built relationships with members and guests by welcoming them into the climbing community
- Managed employees and the flow of the daily schedule to insure a safe and fun environment
- Upheld a clean environment, provided tours to advertise the facility's offerings, and taught new climbers the ins and outs of rock climbing
- Promoted the gym by providing information to inquires over the phone, booking group events, and spreading the word about special events
- Engaged with and listened to members and guests to sell them the membership and gear that best fits their individual needs
- Documented any incidents or injuries in reports, inventoried all food, gear, and facility supplies, and monitored cash in the cash registers and safe

Summer Camp Coordinator

Nashville Zoo (Feb 2016 - Aug 2016)

- Managed summer camp staff and all aspects of summer camp- lessons, crafts, games, etc.
- Developed age-appropriate curriculum and activities for multiple camps spanning ages 4-14
- Conducted evaluations on curriculum through surveys offered to campers to assess the impact of the conservation messages that were taught
- Promoted camps by answering phone and email inquiries and assisting families with registration
- Utilized Excel to organize camper registration information and create weekly rosters
- Presented exciting up close animal encounter presentations by using proper animal handling techniques and various interpretation styles

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Along with two fellow Hoofstock Keepers at the Nashville Zoo, I conducted a survey about giraffe and okapi husbandry
 practices across zoos worldwide and presented the results at the 2019 International Giraffid Conference at the Columbus
 Zoo.
- Furthered my professional development by obtaining a certification from the National Association for Interpretation as a Certified Interpretive Guide in Nov 2019.
- Won 1st place in the Nashville Scene's 2016 Best of Nashville contest for best summer camp.
- I had a poster displayed at the American Association of Zoo Keeper's National Chapter's 2015 Regional Symposium on the progress I made in establishing target training and desensitization training with the arapaima in the Smithsonian National Zoo's Amazonia exhibit.
- In 2013, I traveled to Karongwe Game Reserve in South Africa for a volunteer abroad program through GVI. I assisted with their reserve management by using telemetry to track implanted animals to collect data on the animal's location, behavior, full rating, and prey preference.
- In 2010, I traveled to the Amazon Rainforest in Peru for a Tropical Field Ecology course through Towson University where I conducted my own research project at Cocha Cashu Biological Station. I surveyed the bird species on both Cocha Cashu Lake and the Manu River to see if there was a significant difference in which species used which body of water and what they were using it for. I conducted statistical analysis using SPSS and wrote my findings in a research paper.